cleartrip.sa 2017-07-08

# Privacy Policy | Cleartrip

### Cleartrip is fanatical about protecting your privacy.

This website is published and maintained by Cleartrip MEA FZ LLC (“Cleartrip”). The Privacy Policy is applicable to the websites of Cleartrip MEA FZ LLC including www.cleartrip.ae along with affiliate sites om.cleartrip.com, bh.cleartrip.com, qa.cleartrip.com, kw.cleartrip.com and www.cleartrip.sa which also comprises of the mobile site, Smartphone App Platforms such as iOS, Android, Windows (all together referred to as “Site”). This privacy policy does not apply to the websites of our business partners, corporate affiliates or to any other third parties, even if their websites are linked to the site. We recommend you to review the respective privacy policy statements of the other parties with whom you interact. 

By browsing, visiting, accessing and/or using the services on this Site (or searching for any of the pages on this Site), the customer (“You”) explicitly consents and agrees to our Privacy Policy laid out herein. You also agree that the information furnished by you is lawful, true and correct and does not violate or infringe any laws. In case of any violations, infringement, furnishing of wrongful or unauthorized information, Cleartrip shall not be liable for the same. 

We encourage you to review our Privacy Policy, and familiarise with it. Please note that we review our Privacy Policy from time to time, and we may make periodic changes to the policy in connection with that review. Therefore, you may wish to bookmark this page and/or periodically review this page to make sure you have the latest version of the Privacy Policy. 

### What information does Cleartrip collect, collate and/or use?

On your accessing of this Site, certain information about you, such as :

  1. **Personally Identifiable Information** like name(s) and contact details which may include e-mail address or contact number(s), password etc.
  2. **Transactional Information** like financial information such as Bank account or credit card or debit card or other payment instrument details etc.
  3. **Booking information** which includes information about the travel, bookings, co-passengers, travel preferences etc.
  4. **Other information** that may be requested or gathered while you visit, access or use the Site.

Besides the above, when you browse the Website, Cleartrip may collect information regarding the domain and host from which you access the Internet, the Internet Protocol address of the computer or Internet Service Provider you are using, and anonymous site statistical data, information furnished while navigating the Site, the systems and programs used and the time spent on our Site along with any other relevant information. The Website uses cookie and tracking technology depending on the features offered. Aggregate cookie and tracking information may be shared with third parties to cater to provide you a better service and experience.

We may also collect and furnish such other information as is required in compliance of various laws, court order, as requested by other government or law enforcement authority, or in the good faith believe that disclosure is otherwise necessary or advisable including, without limitation, to protect the rights or properties of Cleartrip or any or all of its affiliates, associates, employees, directors or officers or when we have reason to believe that disclosing the information is necessary to identify, contact or bring legal action against someone who may be causing interference to our operations rights, interests, whether intentionally or otherwise, or when anyone else could be harmed by such activities.

### What is this information used for?

  * To conduct bookings, ticketing and payment transactions for the services available on the Site;
  * To personalize your experience and give you better service: (your information helps us to better respond to your individual needs)
  * To improve the user friendliness of the site; (we continually strive to improve the site offerings based on the information we receive from you)
  * To improve customer service (your information helps us to more effectively respond to your customer service requests and support needs)
  * Website traffic analysis
  * To administer a contest, promotion, survey or other site feature
  * To send emails, SMS and other communications for providing services, responding to inquiries, and/or other requests or questions.
  * To respond to queries of the authorities in regard to your accessing of the site and services availed by you.
  * Automatic Logging of Session Data

Of course, you are solely responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your passwords, and your Site membership account information. Please be very careful, responsible, and alert with this information, especially whenever you’re online. 

### Cookies and how do we use it?

Cookies are small files that a site or its service provider transfers to your computers hard drive through your Web browser (if you allow) to enables the sites or service providers systems to recognize your browser and capture and remember certain information. Yes, we use cookies to understand and save your preferences for future visits and keep track of advertisements. This helps us to serve you better and more efficiently, and to personalize your experience at our Website.

Similarly, a cookie may be placed by our third – party advertising companies or advertisement providers. These companies may use aggregated statistics about your visits to this and other websites in order to provide you advertisements about travel – related goods and services, your preferences in or any goods and services of potential interest to you. The third – party advertising companies or advertisement providers may also employ technology that is used to measure the effectiveness of our ads, your preference and other relevant statistical data to serve you better. Any such information may be anonymous about your visits to this and other sites and does not link online actions to an identifiable person. Mostly the Web browsers are programmed to automatically accept cookies but if you desire to opt from receiving the cookies you can do so by changing the options on your web browser or using certain software programs, you can control how and whether the cookies will be accepted by your browser. Cleartrip does respects your right to block any unwanted Internet activity, especially that of unscrupulous websites, though blocking cookies from usage of Cleartrip Site may disable certain features on the Site, and may make it impossible to purchase or use certain services available on the Site. Please note that it is possible to block cookie activity from certain websites while permitting cookies from websites you trust, like Cleartrip Website.

Mostly the Web browsers are programmed to automatically accept cookies but if you desire to opt from receiving the cookies you can do so by changing the options on your web browser or using certain software programs, you can control how and whether the cookies will be accepted by your browser. Cleartrip does respects your right to block any unwanted Internet activity, especially that of unscrupulous websites, though blocking cookies from usage of Cleartrip Site may disable certain features on the Site, and may make it impossible to purchase or use certain services available on the Site. Please note that it is possible to block cookie activity from certain websites while permitting cookies from websites you trust, like Cleartrip Website.

We do not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to outside parties your personally identifiable information. However, we do transmit your information to trusted third parties who assist us in operating our website, conducting our business, or servicing you, so long as those parties agree to keep this information confidential. We may also the release your information when we believe release is appropriate to comply with the law, enforce our site policies, or protect ours or others rights, property, or safety. However, other non-personally identifiable visitor information may be provided to other parties for marketing, advertising, or other uses.

### Third party links

Cleartrip Site contains links to other websites. Please note that when you click on one of these links, you are entering another website for which Cleartrip has no responsibility and these third party sites have separate and independent privacy policies which you will have to acquaint yourselves with. We encourage you to read the privacy statements of all such sites as their policies may be materially different from our Privacy Policy. We therefore have no responsibility or liability for the content and activities of these linked sites. Nonetheless, we seek to protect the integrity of our site and welcome any feedback about these sites.

### Grievance policy

Cleartrip strongly believes in a sincere and transparent approach to its users. You trust and love us and we would never put growth before trust. This policy document aims at minimizing instances of privacy breach or any privacy related issues via channelized approach, review and redressal.

You can file a grievance / share feedback if you want to report any privacy breach or any privacy related issues.

In order to make Cleartrip redressal channels more meaningful and effective, a structured system has been put in place. This system will ensure that the complaints are redressed seamlessly and well within the stipulated timeframe.

### How to reach Cleartrip for privacy related Issues

For concerns regarding our Privacy Policy or our privacy practices and related Issues, write to us at [privacy@cleartrip.com.](mailto:privacy@cleartrip.com)
